制作: 星际迷航中国字幕组 (https://www.startrekchina.org)
翻译: 凌塔 & 伊伊 & SpadesA & michailxia4 & jynp & AngryKop & 星空下的小狐狸 & NCC1015 & 草一尒
校对: Imprinting & narwhrl
时轴: narwhrl
特效: narwhrl
日期: 2025-08-12
《星际迷航：新世界》前情提要
Previously on Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
这是科尔比博士
This is Dr. Korby.
一开始她只是学生 但事情很快发生了变化
At first she was a fellow, but she quickly became more.
她和我之前一块在瓦迪亚九星管理考古发掘点
She was running the excavation site on Vadia Nine with me.
瓦肯人有一种古代技艺
Vulcans have an ancient technique
能通过冥想来调节疼痛
of regulating pain through meditation.
当我们心灵融合的时候
When we joined minds,
我吸纳了您的痛苦
I absorbed your pain.
我看到了什么
I saw something.
它感觉既像是您的一部分 又不是
It felt both a part of you and not.
是戈恩吗
Was it Gorn?
我认为这种愿意尝试新事物的态度非常适合你
This openness to new life experiences suits you.
好吧 这是谁
Okay. Who's this?
我弟弟
My little brother.
星际舰队公关部
Starfleet's Public Relations.
有意向让我拍一部
They may commission
星际舰队的纪录片电影
a feature-length documentary of Starfleet.
初级医疗官日志
Junior medical officer's log,
星历2184.4
stardate 2184.4.
联邦星舰进取号报告
Reporting from the USS Enterprise.
进取号这个词
Enterprise.
我怎么说都说不厌
I will never get tired of saying that.
能在这里任职六个月简直太棒了
The last six months stationed here have been awesome.
今天我也像往常一样
Today started out like any other day here,
在医务室工作着
me working in sickbay.
但我知道过完今天
But after today
我的生活将被彻底改变
I know my life is never gonna be the same again.
噢 真激动 可不是吗
Oh. Exciting, isn't it?
是啊 如果你对这个课题感兴趣
Yeah, if you're into that sort of thing.
查普尔护士和科尔比博士就要创下历史了
Nurse Chapel and Dr. Korby are about to make history.
嗯 这可能会改变我们对生死的认知
Well, this could change the way we view mortality.
以及科尔比对分子存储器和
And Korby's work on molecular memory
转移实体的研究
and corporeal transference.
甚至古人痴迷的那些
The idea that ancient man's fascination
所谓复活与轮回论
with resurrection and reincarnation
居然其实是被人遗忘的古老科技吗 你看这
could all be based on forgotten technology? I mean...
如果你对这个课题感兴趣
If you're into that sort of thing.
我只是看过他的一些论文
I may have read some of his papers.
我需要考虑把你转配到考古医学部吗
Should I expect a transfer request from you to archaeological medicine?
千万别
Never.
我是说 去古老的星球上挖土
I mean, as fun as it sounds to dig up old worlds
寻找尘封的古代医疗技术是有意思
and find lost medical science,
但我更喜欢现在的岗位
I like where I'm at.
那么 如果你也想创造历史
Well, you can make your own mark on history
你可以赶紧趁着巴特尔舰长还没来
by charging the dermal wands at all the biobed stations
先去给生物床里所有的真皮再生器充能
before Captain Batel gets here for her treatment.
收到长官 这就去
Gotcha, sir. On it.
你确定进取号的偏导阵列
You're sure the Enterprise's deflector array
不会压掉那片磁场异象吗
won't overpower the magnetic anomaly?
我到底需要向你保证多少次不会出事的
How many times do I have to promise you it's all gonna be fine?
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
你有没有和派克说过 这个地方对当地人
You, uh, you let Pike know how-how sacred this place was
来说是非常神圣的
to the people here, right?
你真以为星际舰队
Do you really think
会过去随意搞事 肆意挥舞相位枪
that Starfleet is just gonna waltz on in there,
到头来夷平一个文化遗址吗
phasers blasting, and obliterate a heritage site?
呃 不觉得
Uh, no.
但这也不能怪我吧 我是说
But-but-but can you blame me? I mean...
有些时候习惯于发号施令的人
sometimes people that-that are used to giving orders struggle
轮到他们接受命令时就会犯难
when-when receiving them, huh?
天哪 你可说到点子上了
God, you're so right.
我都想去给派克舰长来一针
I'm just gonna go and hypospray Captain Pike
这样他就不会把差事都往咱们身上扔了
so he doesn't give us, like, any trouble at all.
多少剂量的塔拉嗪才不致死来着
How much Tarazine is sublethal?
我老是记错这些数字
Just always get the numbers all mixed-up.
笑我很好玩吧
You having fun?
要不给他一枪爆头算了
Maybe just a blow to the head?
指令功能是左半脑负责 对吧
Command function's left lobe, right?
嗯哼 嗯哼
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
好吧 听着 我可能是有点偏执了
Okay, look, maybe I'm being a little paranoid.
你吗 亲爱的
Oh, you, my dear?
才没有
Never.
好吧
Okay.
我知道为了说服派克舰长帮忙
I know how much work you've, you've put in,
你做出了多大的努力
lobbying Captain Pike to help.
要是没有星舰
There's just no getting below
我们可没法下到星球表面
the planet's surface without a starship.
我的感激难以言表
And I am more than grateful.
-我只是经常在开工之前 -你总是在开工之前
-It's just that I always get nervous... -You always get nervous
感到紧张
...before a dig.
我知道
I know.
一会见 罗杰
I'll see you soon, Roger.
好 会见的
Yes, you will.
动作快点
Hurry down.
别让我等太久
Don't make me wait.
查普尔
Chapel.
呃 问一句
Uh, quick question.
史波克现在怎么样
How's Spock doing?
应该还好吧
Fine?
今天我没见着他
I haven't seen him today.
他有说什么关于罗杰的事吗
Has he, uh, said anything about Roger being here?
呃
Um...
你看 我知道你们俩
I mean, I know you guys have been...
最近几个月
spending more time, getting closer
-走的还挺近的 -噢不
-these last months. -Oh. No.
求你别跟其他女人一样当醋坛子
No, please don't be one of those women.
这就是为什么我不谈恋爱
This is why I don't do this.
我吗 不是不是
Oh, me? No. Oh.
才不是
Heck no.
我不介意
I'm good.
史波克和我明确地谈过
Spock and I made it very clear with each other.
不要互贴标签 不要把对方期望得太高
No labels, no complicated expectations.
只要过得开心就好
Just fun times.
拜托 别把事情又弄麻烦了
Please don't make it weird.
这样你真的能接受吗
Uh, y-you're good with that?
听着 如果你真的担心
Look, if you're really worried about
史波克会不会去骚扰科尔比 你可以直接问他
Spock behaving around Korby, then just ask him.
毕竟我们都是成年人了
We're all adults here, right?
对
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
实在不可思议 史波克的才智加上
It's amazing. With Spock's brain,
姆'本加的研究 和查普尔精湛的基因技术
M'Benga's research, and Chapel's genetic expertise,
说实话 这真是
frankly, it's a...
别说这是奇迹
Don't say "miracle."
好吧
Okay.
尖端科学的硕果
Top-notch science.
我最喜欢的病人怎么样啦
How's my favorite patient doing?
挺好的
Great, actually.
谢谢你 约瑟夫
Thank you, Joseph.
为了你所做的一切
What you've done here,
我欠你个大人情
I owe it to all of you.
真皮再生器怎么样了
How are the dermal wands looking?
一切就绪 长官
All accounted for, sir.
所有生物床都充好能了
Every biobed station fully charged.
远程同步器呢
And the remote synthesizers?
我就知道你会问 所以我把它们也重新充能了
I thought you would ask, so I recharged them, too.
很好 那你就不会迟到了
Good. So you won't be late.
呃 迟到什么
Uh, late for what?
任务简报
The mission brief.
外勤队成员都要去开会
The landing party's meeting soon.
什么外勤队
The landing party?
瓦迪亚九星的外勤队吗
On Vadia Nine?
你不是已经请求过六次加入外勤队了吗
You've requested away team assignment six times.
你值得的
You've earned it.
别让我在科尔比博士面前丢脸就行
Just don't embarrass me with Dr. Korby.
抱歉 我只是太激动了
I'm sorry. I'm just so excited.
走吧
Go.
要不然他们可不等你了
They'll start without you.
这是第一个正式
My first official research mission
交给我的外星研究任务
on an alien planet.
这可是自我进入星际舰队学院以来
I've been dreaming of this since I was first accepted
就梦寐以求的事情
to Starfleet Academy.
而现在正是我大展拳脚的时候了
And now it's my time to shine.
史波克少校
Lieutenant Spock.
为什么每次我们需要谈谈的时候你总是这么安静
Why are we always so quiet when we need to talk?
有什么需要谈的吗
Is there something to discuss?
我呢
I am...
很高兴看到你和努尼恩辛格上尉
glad to see you and Lieutenant Noonien-Singh
在一起待的时间更久了
spending more time together.
她是一位优秀的舞蹈老师
She is an excellent dance instructor.
这也很好啊
That, too.
呃
Um...
罗杰对发掘工作有些紧张
Roger's... feeling nervous about the dig.
然后 呃
And, um...
就是 我知道你们俩现在差不多 交上朋友了
you know, I know you guys are, like, friends now...
相对来说没错
A relative term.
我只想确保事情进展顺利 不要干扰到工作
I just want to be s-sure that things are gonna go smoothly down there.
你不信任我
You do not trust me.
不用担心 克莉丝汀
Not to worry, Christine.
我制定了必要的保障措施
I have instituted certain safeguards
来保证一切工作顺利进行
to ensure it will all go smoothly.
你这是什么意思 什么措施
What do you, what do you mean, "safeguards"?
啊 太好了 同伴们
Ah, great! Crewmates!
我不用一个人参加简报会啦
I don't have to go into the briefing alone.
我是不是打扰你们说话了
I interrupted something, didn't I?
玛克戎人已经不止一次
The M'Kroon have declined Federation membership
拒绝加入联邦了
on multiple occasions,
所以他们只允许派出一个小型外勤队
which is why they're only allowing a small landing party.
好了 查普尔 你要先亲自上阵
All right, Chapel, you'll be boots on the ground.
一旦信号增强器就位 就通知我们出发
Give us the go-ahead once the signal amplifiers are in place.
科学小组的人已经调整好偏导阵列了吗
Has the science team finished adjusting the deflector arrays?
是的
Yes.
之后我会留驻在进取号上
And I will be monitoring the adjustments in real time,
实时监测这些调整的情况
here aboard the Enterprise.
留在舰上观测数据
Monitoring from the ship
就是你的保障措施
as a safeguard.
你不打算下到星球表面上
You're not coming down to the planet.
查普尔 这是你的任务
Chapel, this is your mission.
还有其他
Any last...
想法或是想说的吗
thoughts or words?
你能再讲一次吗
Could you do that again?
奥特加斯先生
Mr. Ortegas.
抱歉 有子空间的静电干扰 我得调整一下
Sorry. I just needed to adjust for subspace static.
-有点妨碍到我的 -奥特加斯先生
-It interferes with my... -Mr. Ortegas,
艾丽卡答应过你不会添麻烦的
Erica promised you wouldn't be a problem.
如果你保持安静 你会拍到更好的画面
You'll get better footage if you just keep it quiet.
对不起
Sorry.
年轻人
Young man,
如果你在工程部有什么想了解的
if there is anything you want to see in Engineering,
什么都行
anything at all,
我非常乐意能为你
I am more than comfortable
上一上镜
around a camera.
你知道的 佩利亚 咱们别鼓励这种
You know what, Pelia, let's not encourage...
甘布尔少尉
Ensign Gamble,
能请你给我们读读任务简报的第一段吗
would you kindly read the first paragraph of our mission brief?
「为了纪念联邦成立一百周年
"To commemorate the Federation's centennial,
纪录片制作人温贝多·奥特加斯
"documentarian Humberto Ortegas
已经获得了安全许可
"has been given security clearance
以便记录进取号最近执行的任务」
to record Enterprise's current roster of missions."
好吧 既然如此 我们就是绑在一根绳上的蚂蚱了
Okay, according to that, we're stuck with each other.
但希望你能尽量别让相机那么碍事
But maybe just try to keep the cameras out of the way.
一起来发掘过去吧
Let's go dig up the past.
奈杰尔
N'Jal.
多谢你允许我们记录下这个
Thank you for allowing us to document this...
历史性的时刻
historic occasion.
幸会幸会 这是我的荣幸
It is such an honor to meet you.
我听说玛克戎人的声域十分奇特
I hear the M'Kroon have a unique vocal range.
来吧
Come.
让我给你瞧瞧
Let me show you.
嗨
Hi.
你还好吗
How are you?
还不错
Good.
这就是那个磁场异象吗
Our magnetic anomaly?
你说得对 这个地方
You were right about this place.
确实存在某种先进的技术
There is indeed some form of advanced technology
就藏在我们脚下
hiding beneath us.
我们开始吧
Let's set up,
看看它是什么
see what it is.
好啊
Okay.
这东西让你忙了好久吧
They keep you busy, huh?
我们平时一般没机会摆弄玩具
We don't all get to play with toys.
来这里
Come here.
我给你看个东西
Let me show you something.
这个设备操作起来很简单
So, it's intuitive.
人工智能镜头会追踪说话过程中动作和语调的变化
A.I. lenses track movement and inflections in speech
记录下其中隐含的强烈情绪
that indicate strong emotions.
它能记录下言外之意的暗示吗
Uh, it clocks nonverbal cues?
它总是会寻找各种隐台词 激烈的情绪
It's always looking for the subtext, the heat.
也许正是因此 它聚焦在我们身上了
Could be why it's focused on us right now.
搞定了 乌乎拉
Done here. Uhura.
你们那边进展怎样
How's it going over there?
完成啦
Finished.
查普尔呼叫舰桥 传输塔已部署
Chapel to the bridge. The pylons are set.
随时待命
Ready when you are.
收到 准备接收偏导波束
Copy. Stand by for deflector beams.
舰长 我们需要规模更大的外勤队
Captain, we're gonna need a bigger landing party.
我就知道你会下来
I knew you'd have to come down
亲自看看这些的
and see this all for yourself.
我跟你说啥来着 你欠我一顿酒
What'd I tell you? You owe me a drink.
玛克戎人否决了我们增员的请求
The M'Kroons vetoed our request to send more personnel,
所以只有史波克和我来了
so Spock and I are the only ones coming.
明白了
Copy that.
我们找到了一个访问面板
Uh, we found an access panel
上面有不明语言的字符
with symbols in an unknown language.
这些字符是操作界面吗
These symbols are the interface?
也许吧 或者是使用说明
Maybe. Or instructions.
又或者是一种警告
Or a warning.
看起来和玛克戎字母
They have a remarkable similarity
有相当高的相似性
to the M'Kroonian alphabet.
所以 五年前
So, five years ago,
我在几百万光年之外的地方
hundreds of light-years from here,
发现了这个
I discovered this.
我觉得这个标记是皇室的象征
I believe it is a royal insignia.
所以这地方可能是
So this place could be
某种神庙或者宫殿
some sort of temple or palace.
我只知道 这只戒指是在北极星十二号找到的
All I know is, I found this ring on Polaris 12.
但是普莱托利安也上有相似的几组符号
But there are similar symbol sets on Praetorian.
我们那里找到了几块石板
Where we found tablets...
克里斯汀发现上面的文字和
That Christine matched with ancient texts here
瓦迪亚九星的古文相符
on Vadia Nine.
我们认为玛克戎人是
We think the M'Kroon are
某个先进文明的直属后裔
the direct descendants of an advanced civilization
而该文明能够在多个星系间旅行
that could travel across multiple galaxies.
远古宇航员吗
Ancient astronauts?
不得而知
We don't know,
但是他们自称已经获得了永生
but they claim to have achieved immortality.
老生常谈的谬论
A common myth.
众多文明都共有的一类幻想
A fantasy many cultures share.
但我们的研究显示 这个文明
But in this case our research suggests that
实现永生的秘密
their secret to immortality...
有可能涉及到在分子层面上
Had something to do with creating quantum instability
制造量子不稳定现象
at a molecular level.
有意思
Fascinating.
是吧
Right?
总之 我交叉对比了这些字符
Okay, so I cross-referenced the symbols
以普莱托利安语和玛克戎古文为参考
with Praetorian and ancient M'Kroonian.
「救赎之道 就在自愿血祭之中」
"The path to absolution, only with blood given freely."
自愿血祭
Blood given freely?
一种祭祀礼仪 给神明的献礼
A ritual sacrifice. An offering to the gods.
血祭魔法
Blood magic.
在玛克戎上 我们的祖先会自我献祭
On M'Kroon, our ancestors would sacrifice
以来到时间众神的面前
to stand before the deities of time.
喔 等等
Whoa, hold on.
等一下
Just take a moment
先别急着干这么戏剧化的事情
before we choose the dramatic option.
别
Don't.
认真的吗
Really?
它奏效了
It worked.
你的血里没有检测到外来成分
Nothing foreign detected in your bloodstream.
疼吗 有没有什么症状
Any pain, symptoms of any kind?
我没事 少尉
I'll live, Ensign.
好吧 查普尔 这是你的主场了
Well, Chapel, this is your party.
我猜你会想和我一起走
I'm guessing you want to come with me on point.
小心脚下 别碰任何东西
Watch your footing and try not to touch anything.
不幸的是 我来这里就是为了碰东西的 中尉
Sadly, that would defeat my entire purpose here, Lieutenant.
好吧 你知道我什么意思的
Well, you know what I mean.
和星舰的联系断了
Comms on the ship are down.
也就是我们得去外面跟他们汇报
Which means we'd have to go outside to report back.
更重要的是
More importantly...
神庙内不能用传送器
We cannot transport from inside this chamber.
情况很不理想
Far from ideal.
这儿开了
It's open here.
有什么光学障碍在那边
Some kind of light barrier.
行吧 不管这是什么 我不喜欢它
Yeah, whatever it is, I don't like it.
害怕夜魔了吗
Scared of El Cucuy?
我又不是五岁小孩 而且这也不是睡觉时间
I'm not five, and it's not my bedtime.
那是什么 一个巨大的
Hey, what's that, an oversized...?
袋子 我本来要说 袋子
Bag. I was gonna say bag,
但这是尸体
but, nope, it's a body.
好吧 他们不是永生的
Well, they're not immortal.
读数显示这些残躯已经有几百个年头了
The readings indicate these remains are centuries old.
死因应该是饥饿
Cause of death appears to be starvation.
他们被困在这儿了
They were trapped down here.
只是一种直觉 但是我寻思
Just a hunch, but it looks to me
他们应该是来盗墓的
like they were trying to rob the place.
这么看来 这次任务的风险更高了
This discovery raises the threat level of the mission.
我们必须离开 向舰长汇报
We must exit, report this to the captain,
重新评估这次调查的可行性
and reassess our investigation.
等一下
Hold on a second.
不是克莉丝汀在主管这次任务吗
Isn't Christine in charge of this mission?
其实 史波克是高级科学官
Actually, Spock is the senior science officer.
但我不用听星际舰队的 不是吗
Well, I don't answer to Starfleet, now, do I?
听着 这种风险忽然变大
Look... this is not the first time
但还不构成致命威胁的情况
that a landing party mission has faced
外勤队已经不是第一次见了
escalated but not lethal danger.
星际舰队的规章明确规定了
Starfleet protocol clearly states
外勤队必须警告星舰
a landing party must alert the ship
告知一切明确存在的威胁
to any clear and present danger.
-但什么危险的事都还没发生呢 -史波克
-But nothing dangerous has happened. -Spock,
我们在这里的发现实在是太重要了
wh-what we can discover here is important.
不只是对我 也不只是对罗杰
Not just to me, not just to Roger.
甚至不只是对于科学而言
Not even just to science.
奈杰尔 玛克戎人
N'Jal, the M'Kroons,
这是他们的历史
this is their history.
就像你说的 这不只和我们有关
As you've stated, this is not just about us.
奈杰尔 在这里 我们是你的客人
N'Jal, we are your guests here.
你希望我们撤退还是继续调查
Would you prefer if we cease or proceed?
最贴切的翻译是
Closest translation:
「我的人民一直殷切地希望」
"My people have a deep desire.
「能知道我们民族的内核」
We wish to know the core of our being."
信任是双向的 史波克
Trust is a two-way street, Spock.
我们将继续执行任务
We will continue with the mission.
我帮你
I got you.
罗杰
Roger.
这是一块忆石
It's a memory stone.
和我们在普莱托利安上找到的一样
It's just like the ones we found on Praetorian.
克莉丝汀 这个
Christine, this...
这正是我们来这里要找的东西
this is exactly what we came here to find.
小心点
Careful.
甘贝尔
Gamble!
甘贝尔 甘贝尔 你没事吧
Gamble, Gamble, Gamble, Gamble, you okay?
放松 放轻松 你会没事的
Easy, easy. I've got you.
我们刚把碎片送去佩利亚那里分析了
We just sent the fragments to Pelia for analysis.
他一捡起这个球体 它就被激活了
The orb triggered when he picked it up.
让小队其他人集合
Gather the rest of the team
然后马上传送回舰
and beam back aboard immediately.
收到 舰长
Understood, Captain.
甘贝尔怎么样了
How's Gamble?
状态稳定下来了
He's stable.
姆'本加正在
M'Benga's already working on
给他设计一对新的眼睛
bioengineering him new eyes.
我们找到了一些东西
We found something.
我想这是什么登记表吧
I think this is some kind of register.
这里有几千个名字
There are thousands of names here.
其中的一些也被写在了那些尸体附近的古物上
Some of which are actually on the artifact you found among the dead.
大伙们 在这里我们是可以学到很多东西
Guys, this is great, and there's so much to learn here,
但我们该走了
but it's time to go.
我们该回舰了
We got to get back to the ship.
奈杰尔和我 我们两个要留下
N'Jal and I are, are gonna stay behind.
像这样的发现 我等了一辈子
Waited my whole life for a find like this.
罗杰
Roger.
嘿
Hey.
看看这个
Look at this.
这是什么
What is it?
我让一个摄像头穿过走廊去看看了
I sent a camera through the doorway.
什么时候干的 我们已经要离开了
Before or after we said to pull out?
这是隔壁房间吗
That's the next chamber?
呃
Um...
他说的什么意思
What's he saying?
「危险」
"Danger."
不是「危险」
Not "danger."
是「恶魔」
"Evil."
奈杰尔 发生什么了
N'Jal, what's wrong?
我们都死定了
We're all gonna die.
奈杰尔 奈杰尔
N'Jal. N'Jal!
门关了
The door.
你好 有人在吗
Hello? Who's here?
为什么这么黑
Why is it dark?
尽量先不要坐起来
Try not to sit up.
是戴着这个我才看不见吗
Is this why I can't see?
不
No.
你的眼球被从眼眶里拽出来了
Your bulbus oculi were ejected from their orbital sockets.
我眼睛没了?
I lost my eyes?
这个仪器本应该帮你再生出一对眼睛来
This should be regenerating them.
但现在 它只能防止伤口进一步的恶化
But right now it's just keeping them from deteriorating further.
我是什么时候受伤的
When was I injured?
你在那颗星球上被某种手雷击伤了
You were injured on the planet by a grenade of some type.
我们还在分析手雷碎片
We're still analyzing the fragments.
外勤队呢 他们还好吗
The landing party? Are they okay?
其他人没有受伤
The others are fine.
他们很快就会传送回来
They should be back here any minute.
我的短期记忆受损了
My short-term memory was damaged.
希望不是永久的
Hopefully, it's not permanent.
这是创伤后的应激反应
A post-traumatic stress response.
他状态怎么样
Status?
意识清醒 很警惕
Conscious. Alert.
而且很害怕 但很庆幸活下来了
And scared but happy to be alive.
理解 情有可原
Well, that's understandable.
休息一会吧 我马上就回来
Rest. I'll be right back.
好吧 给我完整的报告
All right, what's the full report?
我要更改我最初的诊断
I've shifted my initial assessment
这不是简单的闪光灼伤
from flash burn
而是某种智能体造成的
to some kind of agent.
生物武器吗
Biological weapon?
有可能
Maybe.
没有传染性 以防你要问
And before you ask, he's not contagious.
但有什么东西在阻止他的眼睛再生
But something is preventing his eyes from regenerating.
那你还好吗
Okay, how are you holding up?
我还好
I'm fine.
你知道 甘贝尔原本是来替班查普尔的
You know, when Gamble came on to replace Chapel,
本来是暂时性的顶替 但她回来之后
it was supposed to be temporary, but she came back.
而他留在这里了
And he stayed.
大家都看得出来我很喜欢那个孩子
It's no secret I'm fond of the boy.
他还没准备好出外勤任务
He wasn't ready for away missions.
约瑟夫 你比谁都清楚
Joseph, you know more than most,
我们不可能保护好所有人
we can't protect everyone.
但能救治他的人非你莫属
But if anyone's going to help him, it's going to be you.
怎么偏偏现在锁上了
It's locked. Why now?
这个建筑肯定启动了安全协议
The structure must have engaged a safety protocol.
克莉丝汀 你和拉安带着甘布尔出去的时候
Christine, it didn't trigger
这个机关还没有被触发
when you and La'An took Gamble through.
你们回来时也没有
Or when you came back.
你开门的时候 它提取了你的DNA样本
When you unlocked the door, it took a sample of your DNA.
你被扫描了
You were scanned.
当时我们是一起进来的
And we all entered together as a group.
你的生物特征保护了大家
Your biosignature kept us safe.
然后 奈杰尔想单独离开
So, N'Jal tried to leave without me.
好吧 这扇门以前还肯认我 现在彻底不认了
Well, if the door liked me then, it's done liking me now.
不 不 肯定有别的出路
No, no, there has to be another way out.
我们都知道 光靠等下去只有死路一条
We know what happens if we try to wait things out.
你是说要继续往建筑深处走？
You are suggesting we go deeper into the structure?
留在这里只会饿死
We stay here and we starve.
无论如何都有风险
Either way is a risk.
我倾向于更主动的选择
I prefer the one that keeps us active.
可以吗
May I?
嗯
Yeah.
拉安
La'An.
贝托的摄像头还在传回另一间房的画面
Beto's camera's still showing the feed from the other chamber.
看起来还算安全
It looks safe, relatively.
所以那个房间就在这扇门后面吗
So that chamber is on the other side of this door?
是的
Yes.
好吧 试试看
Okay, let's try it.
查普尔
Chapel?
说不定这扇门还认你呢
Maybe this door still likes you.
好了
Okay.
成功了
That worked.
为防万一 我们应该保持之前的队形
As a precaution, we should use the same formation as before.
好
Yeah.
以防我们被强光烧成灰吗
Precaution against being incinerated by burning light?
查普尔跟我 乌乎拉跟贝托
Chapel with me. Uhura, Beto.
史波克和科尔比 你们殿后
Spock and Korby, you take up the rear.
看啊
Look at it.
罗杰 这
Roger, this...
他们不见了
They're gone.
等等 我们先想想
Wait. Let's think about this.
-再过去恐怕我们也要走散 -是的
-We could get separated, too. -Yeah.
通讯呢
Huh, what about comms?
我知道我们联系不上星舰 但是
I know we can't reach the ship, but...
也许
Maybe,
也许干扰是来自建筑本身的
maybe the interference is coming from the building itself.
拉安呼叫史波克 收到请回答
La'An to Spock, do you read me?
史波克收到
Spock here, I read you.
科尔比博士和我在一个单独的房间里
Dr. Korby and I appear to be in a room by ourselves.
我们也收到了 是我和贝托
We copy, too. It's Beto and I.
虽然还在一起
Also alone.
但也就只有我们了
Together but alone.
我们还有通讯
We have comms.
勉强算是个好消息吧
I'd call that a silver lining.
好吧
Okay.
都待在原地别动
Stay put wherever you are.
没意见
No arguments here.
同意
Agreed.
你们的房间正中间有个大雕像吗
Do you guys have a giant statue in the middle of your chamber?
我们的房间和刚离开的那个一模一样
Our room looks just like the one we left.
连盗墓贼的尸体都在
Dead grave robbers and all.
或许我们应该勘察一下各自的区域
Perhaps we should surveil our respective areas
然后再汇报
and report back.
好
All right.
我们十分钟后再重新联络
Let's reconvene on comms in ten minutes.
保持警惕
And stay alert.
暂无定论
Inconclusive.
好痒
That tickles.
你醒了
You're awake.
这个根本没用 是吧
This isn't doing anything, is it?
是的 没用
No, it's not.
我到底怎么了 约瑟夫
What's happening to me, Joseph?
你叫我的名字了
You used my first name.
抱歉 姆本加医生
I'm sorry. Dr. M'Benga.
-你说得对 -没事 挺好的
-You're right, I... -No, it's good.
你早该在我面前别那么拘谨了
It's more than time you feel comfortable around me.
看来死里逃生
I guess a close call like that
真的能让人想通一些事
can really put some things in perspective.
这个读数
This reading...
等一下
Hold on.
好了 我们再试一次
All right, let's try this again.
怎么了
What?
是什么 读数怎么说
What is it? What does it say?
我们需要更多测试
We need more tests.
医生
Doctor...
约瑟夫 你就告诉我吧
Joseph, just tell me.
我只能直说了
There's no other way to put this,
你的大脑已经死了
your brain is dead.
扫描显示整个脑叶 所有的电子 神经元
The scan shows entire lobes, electrons, neurons,
全都停止活动了
all shut down.
不可能 那我怎么还活着
No. That's impossible. How am I alive?
我还醒着 还能说话
I-I'm awake, we're talking.
是的 我知道 正如我所说
Yes, I know. Exactly like I said.
我们需要更多测试
We need more tests.
我还没死
I'm not dead!
-嘿 深呼吸 我没说你死了 -不 但是
-Hey, take a breath, I didn't say that. -No, but, but,
我要给你打一针镇定剂 放松
I'm giving you a sedative. Relax.
但是
But--
冷静下来
Stay calm.
我会弄明白的
I'll figure this out.
-查普尔 -嗯?
-Chapel. -Hmm?
为什么这个考古遗址里会出现地球语言
Why is there an Earth language at your ancient dig site?
是中文
It's Chinese.
「永恒之桥的守望者矗立于此」
"Here stands the Beholder, sentry of eternal bridges."
居然有生物信号
A biosignature?
这东西有生命迹象
This thing has a life sign reading.
看着没那么有生气啊
Doesn't act very alive.
哦 严格来说这东西既是活的也是死的
Oh, well, technically, it's both alive and not.
而且 它不是真的在这里
Also, it's not really here.
嗯 反正我正在看着它 所以
Hmm, well, I'm looking right at it, so...
在量子水平上 组成这个守望者的粒子
On a quantum level, the-the particles that make up
是不断变化的
this Beholder are in constant flux.
既在这里也不在这里
Both here and not here.
分子水平上的量子不稳定性
Quantum instability at a molecular level.
真好
Great.
所以这是什么意思
So what does that mean?
完全不知道呢
Not a clue.
那很好了
Brilliant.
这真的是我们之前来过的同一个房间吗
Is this really the same room we were just in?
也许是 但你看
Perhaps, but look.
鉴于奈杰尔的下场 我可不会去那里
I wouldn't go that way after what happened to N'Jal.
你真的觉得那只是个幻想吗
Do you really think it's a fantasy?
你反对永生这个想法吗
You balk at the idea of immortality?
你难道觉得世上不存在科学的手段
You don't think that the science exists
来防止我们的意识消散吗
to prevent our consciousness from fading?
我不反对你的想法 科尔比博士
I do not balk at your ideas, Dr. Korby.
我只是认为你疏于做适当的预防措施
I merely believe you neglect to take the proper precautions.
什么？
Huh?
我是说你疏于做适当的
I said you neglect to take the proper...
不 看这里
No, no, no, no, look here.
在名字上面 这个词 意思是
Above the names, this-this word, it means, um,
寄生虫 或者搭便车的人
parasites or hitchhikers.
还有这个词 意思是井或者是坑
And-and this word, it means well or pit.
这个词 Vezda
This word... Vezda.
Vezda 玛克戎语中的「邪恶」一词吗
Vezda. The M'Kroon word for evil?
是
Yes.
这个词只在这里用过 而且
Only here it's used, Vezda, it-it...
是复数
it isn't singular.
真有意思
Fascinating.
怎么了
What is it?
你看到什么了
What do you see?
这些东西有成千上万个
Thousands of them.
我们的外勤队还没回来
Our landing party never came back.
我弟弟本不该遇到这种事
My brother didn't sign up for this.
所有参与项目的玛克戎联络人
All of the M'Kroon liaisons on the project have
突然进入了无线电静默状态
suddenly gone radio silent.
当地人把我们的联系切断了
The locals have cut us off.
那就再派出一个外勤队
So send down another landing party.
对啊 他们不能阻止我们把我们的人救回来
Aye. They cannot keep us from getting our people back.
不幸的是 他们可以
Unfortunately, they can.
我们签过了特别通行协议
We're here with a special access agreement.
我能向他们求助
I can reach out,
如果大使帮不上忙 我们就自己下去
if the ambassador is no help, we will go down there.
关于我们遇到的这个爆炸装置
What do we know about the explosive device
我们都知道些什么
that we encountered?
从技术上来说
Technically it's a...
这个东西是个收容单元
It's a, it's a containment unit.
就其本身而言 球体不应该发生爆炸
On its own, the orb should not have exploded.
可能是由于它离开了能量源
It's possible it got separated from its power source
然后变弱了
and weakened.
但我们估计 最可能是因为
But best we can figure is
里面的能量源强行冲了出来
that the energy source inside of it forced its way out.
怎么个强行冲出来
Forced its way out, how?
它会不会有自己的意识
Could it have been sentient?
我们无从得知
Oh, we don't know.
佩利亚 你还有什么没告诉我们
Pelia, what aren't you telling us?
这个东西
This thing...
比我见过的所有东西都要古老
is older than anything I've ever seen.
你觉得里面是什么
What do you think was inside of it?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
而且我完全没法科学地解释这一切
And I have no scientific way of putting this,
但不管这东西是什么
but whatever it is,
都让我不寒而栗
it gives me the heebie-jeebies.
甘布尔少尉
Ensign Gamble.
舰长呼叫安全部 到医务室与我会合
Captain to Security. Meet me in sickbay.
露吉雅 多么好听的名字
Rukiya, what a beautiful name.
真可惜你不得不放手
It's a shame you had to let her go.
我没跟你说过露吉雅的事
I never told you about Rukiya.
嗯 是啊
Hmm, you're right.
说漏嘴了
My mistake.
你真以为去找你的那个女人
Do you think that woman who came to you
的确是你女儿吗
was really your daughter?
还是说你觉得有什么东西伪装成了她的模样
Or do you think it was something wearing her skin?
夺走她的泪水 吞噬她的哭喊声的某种存在
Something that drank her tears and fed off her screams?
跟我说话的是谁
Who am I talking to right now?
什么鬼
What the hell?
发生什么了
What was that?
外来的某种智慧生命
A foreign intelligence.
在我体内吗
Inside me?
它怎么能说话的 它在用我来说话
How was it talking? It had my voice.
我还不知道
I don't know yet.
为什么它要说这些东西
Why would it say those things?
放松 深呼吸
Relax. Take a breath.
约瑟夫
Joseph...
我有些不舒服 像偏头痛一样
I'm having a reaction, feels like a migraine.
是你
You.
囚禁者
Cali-katchna!
邪恶之物
Mika-tah, Vezda-pah!
舰长
Captain...
玛丽
Marie!
Marie.
玛丽 是我
Marie, it's me...
别逼我这样做
I don't want to have to do this,
所有人都给我退开
everybody just leave me alone.
冷静
Easy, easy.
甘布尔 是我
Gamble, it's me.
姆'本加医生
Dr. M'Benga?
我本不想这样做的
I didn't mean to do that.
我相信你
I believe you.
求你了 把相位枪放下
Please, put the phaser down.
为什么所有人都想伤害我
Why is everybody trying to hurt me?
他们不是想伤害你 我们是想帮你
They are not, we're trying to help you.
放下武器
Stand down.
给他一些空间
Give him room.
如果我让他们带走我 你会治好我吗
If I let them take me, will you fix me?
我只想重新变回我自己
I just want to be me again.
我会的 不用担心
I've got you, don't worry.
医务室还是禁闭室 长官
Sickbay or the brig, sir?
扫描显示
Scans are showing
这根柱子在现实空间中时隐时现
this pillar is shifting in and out of this reality.
你意思是 这个诡异的地下洞窟变得更诡异了?
You mean the freaky underground hell hole gets even freakier?
我们就要像那些探险家一样死在这了
We're just going to die here like those explorers we found.
嘿
Hey.
看着我
Look at me.
我经历过你这种情况
I've been where you are right now,
我也知道你现在只能满脑子想着
and I know that all you can focus on
这一切有多么糟糕
is how bad this all feels.
我满脑子都是我们单独被困在这里 还有什么东西
All I can think about is being trapped down here alone with...
我们并不孤单
We're not alone.
我们会找到离开这里的方法
We are going to find our way out of this.
我们一起
Together.
只要深呼吸就好
Just breathe.
多谢
Thank you.
这怎么可能
I'm seeing the impossible.
看
Look.
乌乎拉呼叫外勤队
Uhura to landing party,
我想我发现了什么
I think I've got something.
我们也有一些有趣的发现
We have some interesting finds, too.
确实 这里有很多可以讨论的东西
Indeed, there is much to discuss.
这个雕像有不稳定的相位差异
The statue in here is giving off unstable phase variances.
而且它还有生命信号
And it has a life sign.
科尔比和我发现了一种智慧生命的存在
Korby and I discovered the presence of sentient life.
有趣 我不记得有这个伤口
Curious, I do not recall this injury.
好了 这整件事都很奇幻
Look, all of that is amazing.
这整个地方都是 但是重点是
This whole place is, but the thing is
我们其实在同一个房间
we are all still together.
这怎么可能呢
How is that even possible?
直觉型软件系统
The intuitive software,
它检测到了我们的生物信号而且把我们
it's-it's picking up our biosignatures and placing us
所有人放到了一个房间里
all in the same room.
这是一个多层维度的空间
This is layered dimensional space.
我们不是在不同的房间里
We're not in different rooms.
而是在不同的现实位面中
This is different planes of existence.
我们从来都没有离开过第一个房间
We never left the first chamber.
如果亚原子不稳定性就是
If subatomic instability was being
他们达成永生的手段 那么
utilized as a means to immortality, then...
那么这个地方可能是个实验室
Then maybe this place is a lab
或者是什么不老泉
or a-a fountain of youth?
这事恐怕不是这么简单
I fear it is not that simple.
史波克发现这些球里面困有许多生物
Spock found life-forms trapped inside orbs,
和伤害了甘布尔的那个东西一样
just like the one that injured Gamble.
石板上称呼它们为寄生虫 搭便车的人
The tablet called them parasites. Hitchhikers.
不被欢迎的客人
Unwelcome guests.
有可能是因为 通过在不同维度中相移
It is possible phase-shifting through dimensions
来达到永生有副作用
to achieve immortality had a side effect.
或者带来了什么东西
Of bringing something through.
到底是什么东西
What kind of something?
一些从其他地方过来的东西
Somethings... from somewhere else.
如果这个地方不是什么宫殿或者实验室呢
What if this place isn't a palace or a lab?
它会不会是个监狱
What if it's a prison?
对不起 但是我们必须在这里看着你
I'm sorry, but we'll have to look after you from here.
没关系的
It's okay.
我能理解
I understand.
我之后会怎么样
What's gonna happen to me?
我要是知道就好了
I wish I could say.
这句铭文写的是
This inscription reads
「触手可及 但也遥不可及」
"Here and not here."
在普莱托利安上
On Praetorian,
有些文物会被放置在这样的底座上
artifacts were sometimes set into pedestals like this.
那些零部件
Component parts.
只要组装起来 也许就会是
Together they might be the key
把维度偏移合并起来的关键
to unifying the dimensional shift.
浮雕在这里
The relief there.
纹章戒指呢
The signet ring.
还在我这儿
I still have it.
好的 但是该怎么样才能
Okay, but how do we get those
让困在不同的位面里的我们
two things to work together
把这两件东西组合起来
whilst stuck on different dimensional planes?
把浮雕放在写着圣龛的地方
Put the tablet where it says tabernacle.
好了
Done.
乌乎拉 戒指
Uhura, the ring.
好 然后呢
Okay. What now?
我是这一切的关键 对吧
I'm the key to all of this, right?
克莉丝汀
Christine.
越来越奇怪了
Curiouser and curiouser.
好的 所以现在我们重聚在一起了 但是
Okay, so we're all back together, but...
我们怎么到门口去
...how do we get to the door?
你感觉还好吗
How are you?
这是为了以防我又失控吗
In case I go off the rails again?
嗯
Mm.
姆'本加觉得 在确保没有危险前
M'Benga didn't want to release you to the quarters
还不能放你回舱室 不过
without knowing it was safe, and...
我知道我不需要用这玩意
I knew I wouldn't need it.
克里斯 我不知道当时发生了什么
Chris, I don't know what happened in there.
我体内的什么东西突然就失控了
Something inside of me just snapped.
甘布尔怎么样了
How's Gamble?
被监禁着
In custody.
他也不太正常
He's not quite himself, either.
我记得我看到了他 但是
I remember seeing him, but it...
那不是他
It wasn't him.
那是另一个存在
He was something else.
而且我感觉
And I felt...
我也不像自己了
...like something else.
什么意思
What?
我描述不出来
I can't describe it.
我只是遏制不住想杀死
I just had this overwhelming desire to kill...
不对 想抹杀他的冲动
...no, to exterminate him.
至少你现在回来了
Well, you're back now.
其他人对他有过这种反应吗
Has anyone else reacted to him this way?
没有
No.
我们得考虑这是你体内的戈恩基因的表现
We have to consider that it's an expression of the Gorn DNA in your body.
我们不知晓那种疗法还有什么副作用
We don't know all the downsides.
这种感受
This feeling I had,
我解释不清楚
I can't explain it,
但是它感觉很 古老
but it felt... old.
好
Okay.
不论如何 我们会把它弄清楚的
Whatever it is, we'll figure it out.
外勤队怎么样了
The landing party?
仍然失联中
Still missing.
舰长 玛克戎大使正在等待跟你通话
Captain, I've got the M'Kroon Ambassador on standby for you.
把他接过来
Patch it through.
好的
Okay.
所以 我们得想办法到门口去
So, we got to find a way to get to the door.
原来如此
Of course.
在这个被我们重组了的维度空间里
In this reconstituted dimensional space,
倒置的因果律与常规法则共存
inverted causality coexists.
呃 你最好还是解释清楚点
Uh, yeah, you're gonna have to walk me through that one.
因果律倒置是指在某维度中
Inverted causality is a dimension
结果出现在起因之前的现象
where effects can happen before cause.
呃 这是个悖论
It's, uh... It's paradoxical.
是的 这是个理论假设
Yes, and theoretical,
但在科学上也是成立的
but also scientifically possible.
科尔比博士和我被单独分开的时候
When Dr. Korby and I were separated,
这里有一座桥
there was a bridge here.
而门旁的那个面板亮的是白光
And that panel by the door was glowing white.
现在它亮的是红光
Well, it's red now.
是的 所以我们肯定是把它打开了
Yes. So we must have turned it on.
结果出现在起因之前
Effect before cause?
所以你是说 不不
So you're saying... No, no.
不可能
No.
什么 什么不
What? "No, no" what?
没错
Yes.
我们必须走过那片虚空
We must walk across this empty space
并开启那座桥
and turn on the bridge.
警卫 警卫
Guard. Guard!
你的母亲 她正处于痛苦之中
Your mother. She's in pain.
有什么东西正在伤害她
Something's hurting her.
什么
What?
她的名字 叫雅拉
Her name... it's Jara.
她想告诉你是什么在伤害她
She wants to tell you what's hurting her.
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
是你伤害了我 你让我独自死去
You did. You let me die alone.
不行 我才不要这么做 没门
Nope, I-I'm not doing that. No way.
我们的另一个选项是留在这里挨饿
Our other option is to remain here and starve.
相当有意思的战术讨论
A sound tactical argument.
好吧 你打头阵 我跟着你
So... you lead, I'll follow.
别踩到我的脚就行
Just don't step on my toes.
我也愿意冒这个险
I am also willing to take this risk.
然而 我确信我们其实必须
However, I believe that we must, in fact,
一起协力完成这件事
commit to doing this all together.
只有查普尔护士能开门
And Nurse Chapel is the key.
别这么做 克莉丝汀
Don't do it, Christine.
理论成立不代表你真的就可以浮空
Theoretical doesn't mean you can just go and walk on air.
查普尔护士
Nurse Chapel,
涉及许多方面的事情 你也许不如以往那般信任我
I may no longer have your confidence on many things,
但这次我们在谈的是科学
but this is a matter of science.
况且这关系到我们的生死存亡
And what hangs in the balance is our survival.
我们当前最需要的就是双向的信任
We are on a two-way street.
现在 我请求你 只要相信我就行
And now I'm asking you to simply trust me.
罗杰 我们该离开了
Roger, it's time to go.
不
No.
克莉丝汀 理智点啊
Christine, listen to reason.
是 走过去是有风险
Yes, it is a risk walking out there,
但是我们相识的这段不长的时间里
but in the short time that I've known you,
你来都没有害怕过冒险
you've never been afraid of taking a chance.
还记得几个月前你对我说过的话吗
Remember what you said to me, all those months ago?
「人生百态 皆无定数」
"Nothing in life is guaranteed."
那就是人生的意义
That's what makes life worth living.
好吧
Okay.
罗杰 别碰那个古物
Roger, leave the relic where it is.
我们能在一起全靠它了
It's the only thing keeping us together.
好了
Okay.
你看见它在这里了对吧
So this is where you saw it?
是的
Yes.
明白
Okay.
那么
Well...
出发吧
let's go.
我们离开这儿
Let's get out of here.
嘿 我们还活着
Hey. We're alive.
这就够了
Take the win.
输入高级军官指令代码
Senior officer command codes, please,
不然我就杀了你
or I will kill you.
什么 你在说什么
What? What are you saying?
我能看到这小子的思想和记忆
I have the boy's thoughts, his memories.
你能从轮机室超控这整艘船
You can take control of this vessel from Engineering.
镧族人小孩
Lanthanite child.
什么
Wha--
要不换他也行
Perhaps I take him instead?
或者换他
Or him?
敢伤害他们 下一个死的就是你
Hurt them and you die next.
不舍得直接对你最喜欢的少尉动手 是吧
you couldn't kill your favorite ensign now, could you?
救救我 求你了
Help, please.
姆'本加医生 是我 真的是我
Dr. M'Benga, it's me, it's really me.
不要伤害我
Don't hurt me.
抵抗它 你能做到的
Fight it. You can fight it.
不 约瑟夫 我觉得甘布尔已经不在了
No, Joseph, I don't think he's really in there.
他还在
He is.
放了那孩子 求你了
Let the boy go. Please.
占据我的身体吧
Take me.
别
不
你把它传送到哪了
W-Where did you send it?
哪都没传去
Nowhere.
多亏佩利亚和斯考特中尉的随机应变
Thanks to Pelia and Lieutenant Scott's quick thinking,
我们应该不会再见到邪灵了
we should not be seeing the Vezda again.
你确定这能困住它吗
Are you sure it'll hold?
在得到有关这个生命体更多信息之前
Until we learn more about this entity,
既然送不回那个多维监狱
the transport buffer is the best proxy we have
传送缓存器是我们最好的替代方案了
for a layered dimensional prison.
剩下的那些怎么办
What about the rest of them?
星际舰队和玛克戎人正在合作
Starfleet and the M'Kroon are already working together
在遗址周围建立安全防线
to establish a security perimeter around the site.
看来他们开始意识到
Apparently, they're starting to see
加入联邦的好处了
the benefits of the Federation.
要知道 如果甘布尔少尉
You know, if Ensign Gamble, or...
或者说附身他的生命体
rather, the entity inside of him,
当初控制了舰载相位炮系统
had taken hold of the ship's phaser banks...
他差点就能释放所有的邪灵了
He could have set them all free.
你们能想象这样一支宇宙生物大军在银河系肆虐吗
An army of cosmic beings like that set loose on the galaxy?
我很抱歉 医生 我理解你很喜欢那孩子
I'm sorry, Doctor, I know you were fond of the boy,
但他已经不在了
but he was gone.
它们是邪恶的吗 舰长
Were they evil, Captain?
我看过甘布尔的行动记录
I saw the recordings of what Gamble did,
和他说过的话
and the things he said.
世上没有绝对的善恶 孩子
Good and evil are relative terms, son.
胡说 宇宙中存在绝对邪恶
Nonsense. There is evil in this universe,
正如存在绝对的善良
as sure as there is good.
就像世上存在物质 存在光明一样
A-As sure as there is matter, as sure as there is light.
我能感受到
I know...
那个存在非常古老
that being was ancient.
充满恶意
Malevolent.
那种要将世界全部扭曲 腐化
The desire to malign, to pervert...
吞噬的欲望
and consume,
凝聚成了实体
given corporeal form.
如果那些东西
If any of those things...
但凡有一个逃出了那地方
ever escape that well down there...
只能愿上帝保佑了
...God help us all.
你要给它拍张照吗
You want one for the camera?
不用了
No.
不用了 谢谢
No, I'm good. Thank you.
随你便
Suit yourself.
姆'本加医生
Dr. M'Benga?
联系地球的子空间通讯频道已接通
I have the subspace relay to Earth.
谢谢 把通话交给我吧
Thank you. I've got it from here.
您好 我是进取号的约瑟夫·姆'本加医生
Hello, I'm Dr. Joseph M'Benga of the USS Enterprise.
我请求与您通话
I've asked to be the one to call you.
是关于您儿子
It's about your son,
戴纳·甘布尔的事
Dana Gamble.